

class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> Farm_Machinery_and_Equipmen = [

  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the purpose of a plow in farming?",
      options: [
        "A. Planting seeds",
        "B. Harvesting crops",
        "C. Turning and loosening soil",
        "D. Irrigating fields"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Plows are used to turn and loosen soil, making it suitable for planting crops.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which of the following is a common type of tractor attachment used for planting crops?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Seeder",
        "C. Harvester",
        "D. Cultivator"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'A seeder is a tractor attachment designed for planting seeds in the soil.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. What is the purpose of a combine harvester in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Planting seeds",
        "B. Harvesting crops",
        "C. Irrigating fields",
        "D. Spraying pesticides"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Combine harvesters are used for efficiently harvesting crops, particularly grains.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. Which type of equipment is used for spreading fertilizers evenly across a field?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Seeder",
        "C. Sprayer",
        "D. Harrow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Sprayers are designed for evenly spreading fertilizers or pesticides on crops.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the primary function of a disc harrow in farming?",
      options: [
        "A. Planting seeds",
        "B. Breaking up clods of soil",
        "C. Harvesting crops",
        "D. Irrigating fields"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Disc harrows are used to break up clods of soil and prepare a seedbed.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. Which equipment is commonly used for cutting and collecting hay or straw in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Seeder",
        "C. Baler",
        "D. Harrow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Balers are used for cutting and collecting hay or straw into compact bundles.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the purpose of a planter in farming?",
      options: [
        "A. Harvesting crops",
        "B. Irrigating fields",
        "C. Planting seeds",
        "D. Spraying pesticides"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Planters are designed for precisely planting seeds in rows with proper spacing.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. Which of the following is a common type of irrigation system used in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Drip irrigation",
        "B. Combustion irrigation",
        "C. Windmill irrigation",
        "D. Gravity irrigation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Drip irrigation is a method where water is delivered directly to the base of plants, minimizing water wastage.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. What is the purpose of a thresher in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Planting seeds",
        "B. Harvesting crops",
        "C. Spraying pesticides",
        "D. Collecting hay"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Threshers are used for separating grains from the harvested crop.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. Which equipment is used for leveling and smoothing the soil surface in preparation for planting?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Seeder",
        "C. Roller",
        "D. Harvester"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Rollers are used for leveling and smoothing the soil surface before planting.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. What is the primary function of a chisel plow in farming?",
      options: [
        "A. Breaking up clods of soil",
        "B. Planting seeds",
        "C. Harvesting crops",
        "D. Deep tillage"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Chisel plows are used for deep tillage, breaking up compacted soil.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. Which equipment is commonly used for mowing grass or crops in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Seeder",
        "C. Mower",
        "D. Cultivator"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Mowers are designed for cutting and harvesting grass or crops in the field.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. What is the purpose of a boom sprayer in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Harvesting crops",
        "B. Planting seeds",
        "C. Spraying pesticides",
        "D. Collecting hay"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Boom sprayers are used for applying pesticides or fertilizers over a large area.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. Which equipment is commonly used for removing weeds from between rows of crops?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Seeder",
        "C. Cultivator",
        "D. Harrow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Cultivators are designed to remove weeds and loosen soil between rows of crops.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. What is the purpose of a rotary tiller in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Breaking up clods of soil",
        "B. Planting seeds",
        "C. Harvesting crops",
        "D. Tilling and preparing soil"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'Rotary tillers are used for tilling and preparing the soil for planting.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. Which equipment is commonly used for transporting harvested crops from the field?",
      options: [
        "A. Tractor",
        "B. Plow",
        "C. Seeder",
        "D. Harvester"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Tractors are commonly used for transporting harvested crops from the field to storage or processing areas.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. What is the purpose of a grain cart in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Harvesting crops",
        "B. Planting seeds",
        "C. Transporting harvested grain",
        "D. Spraying pesticides"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Grain carts are used for transporting harvested grain from the field to storage or processing facilities.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. Which equipment is commonly used for digging trenches in the soil for planting seeds?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Trencher",
        "C. Seeder",
        "D. Harrow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Trenchers are used for digging trenches in the soil, commonly for planting seeds or laying irrigation pipes.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. What is the purpose of a corn header in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Harvesting wheat",
        "B. Harvesting corn",
        "C. Planting seeds",
        "D. Spraying pesticides"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Corn headers are attachments for harvesters designed specifically for harvesting corn.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. Which equipment is commonly used for aerating and loosening compacted soil?",
      options: [
        "A. Plow",
        "B. Aerator",
        "C. Seeder",
        "D. Roller"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Aerators are used for aerating and loosening compacted soil, improving root growth and water absorption.'
  ),

];
